What is the likelihood of you having someone who looks just like you?
世间有和你长得一模一样的人的可能性有多大？
Would it be a good thing?
这会是好事吗？
And if you did have one, would you want to meet them?
如果真有这样的一个人，你会想要和他见面吗？
Consider how often your facial features are used to identify you.
不妨想想，你的面部特征有多么频繁地被用来识别你的身份。
Your passport, ID card and driving licence all bare your face.
护照、身份证和驾照上，都印有你的面部照片。
To enter your workplace, you likely need to be recognisable. You may need your face to unlock your smartphone and possibly even need it to exclude you from being present at a crime scene.
进入工作场所时，你需要被认出身份才能通行；解锁智能手机时，可能需要用到面部识别；甚至在排查犯罪现场嫌疑人时，你的面部特征也能帮你洗清嫌疑。
The word ‘doppelganger’ refers to a person who looks the same as you, essentially sharing your features; those that you thought were unique to you and your identity.
“分身（doppelganger）”这个词，指的是和你长得一模一样的人——你们有着几乎完全相同的面部特征，而这些特征你曾以为是独属于你、标识自身身份的东西。
Not an identical twin, as a doppelganger has no relation to you.
但分身和同卵双胞胎不同，他们和你没有任何血缘关系。
The idea originated in German folklore. A doppelganger was said to be a spirit-double that replicated every human and beast on earth.
这个概念起源于德国民间传说，传说中，分身是一种灵体复制品，世界上的每个人和每一种动物，都有一个对应的分身。
So, let’s get real.
那么，让我们看看现实情况。
What are the chances of you having one in the first place?
首先，你拥有一个分身的概率到底有多少？
There’s said to be a one in 135 chance of an absolute dead ringer for you existing anywhere in the world, so the chances are pretty low, despite folk wisdom promising you otherwise.
据说，在全世界范围内存在一个和你长得一模一样的人的概率，仅为1/135，这个几率相当低，尽管民间说法说的可不是这么回事。
And the chances of meeting?
而相遇的概率呢？
The mathematical certainty of finding this particular person is supposedly less than one in a trillion!
从数学角度计算，找到这个特定之人的概率，据说还不到万亿分之一！
That said, these statistics may be a good thing.
尽管如此，这样的概率或许反而是件好事。
Historically, having a double hasn’t always been a positive.
从历史来看，拥有一个和自己长相一样的人，并非总是好事。
Back in 1999, an innocent American man, indistinguishable from the real criminal, was sent to prison for robbery, where he stayed for 19 years. In the end, it turned out to be a case of mistaken identity.
早在1999年，一名无辜的美国男子因和真正的劫匪长得毫无差别，被误判抢劫罪入狱，刑期长达19年，最终证实这是一桩身份误认案件。
In a different case, a woman in New York was accused of trying to poison her doppelganger with deadly cheesecake so that she could steal her identity!
还有另一个案例，纽约一名女子被指控试图用有毒的芝士蛋糕毒害自己的分身，目的竟是为了窃取对方的身份！
And, why are people interested in finding their possible doppelganger anyway?
那么，人们为什么会对寻找自己可能存在的分身感兴趣呢？
It may be helpful to look to the past when facial resemblance indicated kinship.
或许我们可以回溯到过去——在那个年代，面容相似往往意味着血缘关系。
Maybe one day you’ll meet your lookalike, but we understand that, after this, you possibly don’t want to!
也许有一天，你真的会遇到和自己长得一模一样的人，但看完这些案例后，你可能就不会再期待这件事了！